# **ASIYANBI MUBASHIR MAYOWA**

## Frontend Software Engineer

+2348108170354 | asiyanbimubashir@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional and Versatile Frontend Engineer who specializes in web and mobile software development with 4+ years of experience building user-friendly applications. I am a proactive team player and have a core strong belief in communication, I am passionately and actively seeking new technologies on the fly to stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements, and also work as a team to build and optimize performance for better achieving comprehensive solutions. In my spare time, I explore the net to pick up new technologies and enjoy socializing. I am Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, ReactNative, Typescript, Redux, Simpler-state plus modern libraries and frameworks.

#### **TECH STACK**

Front End	HTML5, (S)CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES6+), Typescript, ReactNative, Reactjs, Tailwindcss, Styled Component.
Back End	Node.js, Express, Microservices, APIs
Data Stores	MongoDB, MySQL
Operating Systems	Mac OS, Linux Mint, Ubuntu, Windows 11.
Version Control/Deployment	GitHub, GitLab / Vercel, Netlify, AWS, Heroku, Firebase, Eas
Testing	Jest, Cypress, Detox

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### MOBILE ENGINEER | Contract | PIF | Denmark

April, 2023 - present

PIF - Pay it Forward is a platform that makes it easy and fun to send gifts to each other over the phone. PIF hopes to spread joy to the world and contribute to a more generous society. With the PIF app, you can now send a surprise to anyone of your choice and hopefully, that person will - Pay it Forward.

- Created modular, responsive templates using modern techniques and libraries(such as Expo and Eas).
- Worked with a proficient understanding of code conversion tools.
- converted UI mockup design to mobile templates.
- Integrated RESTful APIs into the app.
- Carried out code Reviews as the Mobile Team Lead.
- Deployed the application to both Play store and App store

#### MOBILE ENGINEER | CODEVILLAGE LLC | Ilorin, Nigeria

Sep 2020 – March 2023

Codevillage LLC is a Nigerian-based company that offers customized and managed ICT Solutions to businesses and organizations. Specialization in web and mobile application development, website management and maintenance, SEO, and training people to become software developers.

- Created modular, responsive templates using modern CSS techniques and javascript libraries.
- Worked as a productive and positive team member to code, test, report, and debug operations.
- Worked with a proficient understanding of code conversion tools.
- converted UI mockup design to web templates.
- Integrated RESTful and graphql APIs into applications.
- Worked on web & mobile applications like Ev-voucher, Law-parlance, codevillage website, Koprative & SMS mobile application.

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER | STARTHUB | Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

June 2021 – August 2022

STARTHUB is a Saudi Arabia-based company that offers customized and managed ICT Solutions to businesses and organizations.

- Worked as a mobile & web frontend Engineer.
- coded, tested, reported, and debugged operations as a productive and positive team member.
- collaborated with team members to develop, test and deploy mobile applications like Hayak App, and Hayak Admin Dashboard, Pass ticket App
- Link Hayak app (Playstore) , Hayak app (App store)

#### JUNIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER, FUTUREX | Ilorin, Nigeria

Jan 2020 – Jun 2020

FutureX is the leading provider of digital transformation to small and large businesses going digital or rebranding phase. From the graphics Design, and website hosting to the consumer point.

- Coding, testing, reporting, and debugging processes were all done as an upbeat junior team member.
- implemented system design and database connection with the server under the supervision and review of a senior backend engineer.
- worked on APIs like Movify and Transport.

#### WEB DEVELOPER |Founders Hub | Ilorin, Nigeria

Feb 2019 – July 2019

Founders Hub provides workspaces growth support services to innovative start-up businesses, including academy and incubation programs for entrepreneurs, pitch, and strategy workshops. Offers ICT Solutions to businesses and Economic at large.

- Worked as a front-end web Developer.
- Worked as a productive team player to code, report and debug operations.
- Converting UI mockup design to web templates.
- Built ExchangeRate web App.

- Creating modular, responsive templates using modern CSS techniques and javascript libraries.
- Worked as a productive and positive team member to code, report, and debug operations.
- Converting UI mockup design to web templates.
- Integrating RESTful APIs

#### INTERN | Mustech Electronics Co Ltd | Ilorin, Nigeria

April 2018 - October 2018

Mustech Electronics is a Nigerian based Company that offers Electronics and Embbedded system solutions to numerous organisations and company.

- Worked using Arduino UNO Board and Nano Board as the core Components(processors) in an Embedded system.
- Worked with Arduino IDE to program MicroProcessor Chip.
- Worked in conjunction with team members to model an inverter system.
- Programmed and tested an automatic light-switching system, and a Rain detector system.

## **PROJECTS**

#### HAYAK.SA | JEDDAH, SAUDI

2021 - 2022

Hayak is an app used to explore the beauty of Saudi Arabia including various experiences, destinations, and Saudi Arabian culture.

• <u>Technologies</u>: ReactNative, Expo, TypeScript, StyledComponent, Eas, Node, Express, MongoDB, Firebase, Git, Trello

#### JADEMEDIAPRO | LAGOS, NIGERIA

2021 - 2022

JadeMediaPro helps small and medium-sized businesses grow and achieve their dreams, earn income, and increase their impact in this post-pandemic world by developing innovative as well as sustainable design systems.

• <u>Technologies</u>: Nextjs, TailwindCss, MUI, Emotion, Git, Trello

#### LAWPARLANCE.NG | LAGOS, NIGERIA

2021 - 2022

Lawparlance is an all-in-one legal management tool for law practices. With easy access to past and present shariah court judgments and cases from various states and countries.

• <u>Technologies</u>: TypeScript, Reactjs, TailwindCss, Node, Express, MongoDB, Git, simpler-state

#### EZEE VOUCHER | LAGOS, NIGERIA

2021

Ezee Voucher is a virtual multi-currency-enabled voucher platform for payments and collections across borders. It's a voucher that makes online payments and collections easy for users and merchants. It helps users to experience global real-time point-of-sale payments with zero exchange fees.

• <u>Technologies</u>: TypeScript, Reactis, Node, Express, MongoDB, Git, simpler-state

## **EDUCATION**

B. Eng. Computer Engineering   University of Ilorin   Ilorin, Nigeria  C.G.P.A - 4.42/5.0 (Second class upper), G.P.A - B	2014– 2019
Senior Secondary School Certificate (SSCE)   Five Ways College   Ilorin, Nigeria	2007 - 2013
CERTIFICATIONS	
NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC)	2020
JAVASCRIPT   HackerRank	2020
JAVASCRIPT ALGORITHMS AND DATA STRUCTURE   FreeCodeCamp	2020
RESPONSIVE WEB DESIGN   FreeCodeCamp	2020
AWARDS	
University Scholar   University of Ilorin Scholar of the Year   computer engineering students association	2019 2019
scholar of the fear   computer engineering students association	2019
ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES	
Online Book Manager   University of Ilorin (Electronic Library)   Ilorin, Nigeria	2017
LEADERSHIP POSITION	
LIBRARY PREFECT   Glorious Vision International College	2011

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Communication
- Adaptability
- Problem-Solving
- Fast Learner
- Teamwork
- Effective Time Management

## **PROFILES**

Personal Website https://www.hemsleek.vercel.app LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hemsleek

Twitter: https://twitter.com/hemsleek Github: https://github.com/hemsleek